MD HEDAYETUL ISLAM CHY

+8801829353906 ♦ Chandgaon, Chittagong, Bangladesh islamhedayet67@gmail.com ♦ hedayet13.github.io

I am an electrical engineer with a specialization in embedded systems, bio-surface modeling, medical image processing and coding. Currently, I'm fully captivating in the fields of robotics and biomedical engineering, where I harness my expertise to drive innovation and make a positive impact.

ACADEMIC CREDENTIALS

Master of Electrical and Electronic Engineering, University of Chittagong Bachelor of Electrical and Electronic Engineering, University of Chittagong Expected 2023

2017 - 2021

CGPA: 3.36

WORK EXPERIENCE

UprintBD, R&D Engineer

July 2022 - present

• Reconfigured printing devices and developed a mobile application alongside server for accelerating cloud printing services.

THESIS AND PROJECT

Surface Engineering

Nov 2021 - June 2023

- Designed 3D printed surfaces to reduce fluid splashing and investigated simulations through Ansys Fluent.
- Applying different CFD methods such as Volume of Fluid, Eulerian method etc.
- Optimized various parameters and analyzed the structure with materials such as SLA-resin and PDMS.

Covid-19 ICU Monitoring

Aug 2020 - Mar 2021

- A system that assists hospital personnel in real-time monitoring of patients' bedside displays from a non-covid space. Experienced how a project becomes a product.
- Developed a Python Wrapper for conducting image processing and character recognition algorithms.
- Esp-32 camera for capturing image and send using TCP/IP protocol.
- Devised an cross-platform application that maintain communication with server.

PUBLICATIONS

• Design optimization of anti-splashing targets and simulation of droplet impact on it (Under review) Physics of Fluids - AIP Publishing LLC 8 Sep, 2023

AWARD AND TRAINING

- ICT Division Fellowship, awarded by the Government of the People's Republic of Bangladesh, to support research in the field of bio-surface, 2022
- Former trainee, Ghorashal Training Center, Bangladesh Power Development Board, Palash, Narsingdi, 2021
- One of the top three team selected for National Hackathon 2019, Title: AI and ML recognized stereo camera for Occupational Health and Safety

TECHNICAL SKILLS

PSpice, Proteus, Diptrace, Solidworks3D, Ansys Fluent Electrical & Mechanical Coding Python (comfortable), MATLAB, Javascript, dart Raspberry pi, Esp32-cam, TTGO camera plus, Arduino Microcontrollers Web server & OS Flask, Django, Nodejs, UbuntuOS, KaliOS, Raspbian Data Visualization OriginPro, ParaView etc Others

Flutter, Illustrator, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Microsoft Azure services,

Virtual machine, GCP, Docker etc.